What's going on guys? Welcome back to
another interquity trading video. Today
is going to be a money one. We're going
to be talking everything and anything to
do about liquidity. Everything I have
learned over the course of years and
thousands and thousands of hours of
looking at these charts. So, please sit
back, grab that notepad, and take as
much notes as possible because I'm going
to be pouring my brain into you guys.
All right? So, leave a like, a comment
down below of future videos you want to
see from us. Turn those noties on. Enjoy
this one.
All right, guys. We're going to be
talking about NQ and I'm going to be
showing you guys the power, the true
power of liquidity only even using the
higher time frames, not even hopping
into the lower. We're going to be on the
daily time frame right now and we're
going to break down all of the price
action in front of us right now. And
also, we're going to unfold more as we
move on. Let's talk about this big
sell-off we've had. We can actually even
hop on to the weekly here. The market
kind of topped out here and printed a
top, you could call it, right? And you
can even see we have equal highs. So,
I'm going to mark on this high right
here. And I hope we can all agree why we
have a reason to mark on this high,
right? I'm not just plotting on a random
high. Look how we have this high
respecting this high to the left hand
side. That is price communicating to us,
telling us we have left liquidity at the
highs. So look at this. I plotted it on
not because I'm predicting it, because
the market has literally communicated it
to us. And remember, this is the weekly
time frame. So check this out. For 1 2 3
4 5 6 7 weeks, we had a rapid sell off
to the downside. Think about the
mentality, the mindset of the retail
trader seeing this kind of move to the
downside. Is it's going to entice them.
it's going to induce them to continue
selling. Whether that's going to be
continuations, whatever way they trade,
they want to be selling this market back
down. Now, we have to view it from the
perspective of why did this move occur?
If you look to the left-hand side, we
can all agree that we have all of these
lows built up in the market for us. And
if you continue following them, check
this out. This wick right here tapped
into something on the left hand side.
Now this low tapped into something on
the lefth hand side. So this is like you
can call it like a chain whatever it is.
This is all liquidity here. And look if
I mark this red box on you can see that
we have tapped into this area as well.
The market was building liquidity for
weeks, months. All right. And then
finally big selloff to the downside.
What was the purpose of it? What was the
intention behind it? To clear all of
this liquidity. Okay. If I draw this
line this line on it'll make even more
sense. And now check this out. What do
we have right below? Hope you guys all
see this by now. A liquidity block. So
we can plot on a blue box. Look how the
market taps into this area. And that is
where that bottom in the market is
found. We trap all of the buyers above
this low. Tap into an LB at the extreme.
And look at that reaction coming out of
it. One week, two week, and then finally
this third week. Look at this bullish
closure right away. Guys, I hope you
guys are starting to see more and more
of this, but your eyes should be back to
these highs. Okay, that is the only
logical liquidity point I can see in
front of us right now. These equal highs
set for us. Okay, and remember the
intention behind this move from high to
low was to induce sellers to the
downside. We need to be buying back up.
Remember what I always say. If this trap
move to the downside occurs, any bearish
moves, deem them to be false, use them
to find a buy opportunity back up to the
upside. So, this is the weekly time
frame. We're not going to be taking
entries off the weekly. So, let's hop
into the 1 hour and the 4 hour, and
we'll start breaking down a bunch of
entries on the way back up. Okay, so
ever since we tapped into this higher
time frame liquidity block, which is
going to be the blue box, we can just
drag this over to clean it up. We
reacted. We get a pullback to the
extreme and then boom, we find momentum
and that continuation starts coming in.
From there, we get another little
pullback. We tap into some imbalances
and continue to the upside. Now, if I
mark out this area that we've tapped
into once, look at this, right? And I
mark the whole high. Drag it over.
Remember what we talk about all the time
about where liquidity is? We're not
predicting. We're letting the market
communicate to us. So, look at this.
this high respects this whole area here
telling us that we now have liquidity
above this high. So that's a great
confluence. Use that to your advantage.
And if I play price forward a little
bit. Okay, look what we have done. All
right, I hope everyone's starting to see
this. But we have built a ton of
liquidity. Look at this guys. This is a
4hour time frame. Can you imagine how
many people are getting screwed over in
this type of price action? rangy range
range respecting lows, respecting highs,
still trading in this whole area, this
whole trap area. This is good though
from our perspective with our system. We
want to see this occur. We want to see
this build up in the market. We now view
this low to hold liquidity, right? And
if I open it up on the 1 hour, you can
see why. Again, we're not predicting.
It's literally communicating it to us.
We have this low respecting this low and
going long back up to the upside. Okay?
So that's why I have plotted on this
blue line right here. Perfect. Now if
you look over to the left as well, you
can see all of this has been tapped
into. So this is all liquidity as well.
You could even mark on this. And
coincidence right below we have a
liquidity block. We don't have a reason
to run this low. Why would we run the
low? We just took out a level of
liquidity here and then we went bullish.
Okay? So I don't view any liquidity to
be below this low. We have liquidity to
the upside. We have a reason for us to
push higher. We have a buildup of
buyers, okay? And we have a liquidity
block below. Perfect. Everything checks
the boxes. We need to be taking an entry
once the liquidity is taken. So, boom.
Entry, stop-loss. And don't forget about
our targets, guys. These equal highs
left for us. Done on purpose. Will be
all the way back at the extreme. Okay?
All the way back at the highs. Now,
let's hop into the 4 hour and we'll
start unfolding price.
So look at that rapid sell off to the
downside inducing sellers but not only
inducing sellers trapping buyers. Okay,
once those buyers are trapped again
that's when we are interested in buying
this asset back up to the upside. Okay,
we'll clean up a couple lines here. But
that is going to be entry number one.
And the easiest way to manage this, very
easy, very simple, is as soon as we take
out this high, we can all agree that
liquidity has been taken. So manage your
risk. Maybe it's um roll it to break
even or just tuck it below this low.
Nonetheless, when these highs are taken
out, you need to be managing your
position. Let's play this out a little
bit. And just like that, we run those
highs. So now we can be this 100%. We
can all agree on that, right? Let's
remove this line as well. Okay. And
we're going to go back to the hourly
time frame here. Perfect. Okay. So now
our entry number one, it's played out
pretty nice. We've taken out a high from
the lefth hand side. Since we have taken
out that high, remember, we got to be
being this. You can't just be holding it
full volume and not be um break even. So
be here. I think we can all agree what's
happening in front of our eyes. Again,
let me drag this red box over. Another
buildup of liquidity. So let's follow
along. Buyers induced
after taking out this high. Buyers
trapped. This is where a lot of people
make mistakes. Just because we have
taken out this low here does not mean we
need to buy right away. That is pattern
trading. We do not do that. Look what
the market does. We print this low and
we go long. Remember, sellers are
induced, right? Sellers are selling
these areas. Look what the market does
for us. It reacts off it to build
liquidity. So, there's liquidity above
this high. Now, this is not an area we
want to be selling from because we have
taken out this low. That's something you
need to identify. Just because there's a
reaction does not mean we need to be
involved in it. And we start getting a
reaction back down to the downside.
Right away, look where your eyes need to
go. Back down to this low. Why? We have
liquidity here. Same thing. Look, high
taken out. Low respecting low. That
means price has literally told us, it's
confirmed to us that we have liquidity
below this low. Wait for price to come
below this low. And would you look at
that? We have a another liquidity block
at the low down here. If I drag this
over, the only issue with this liquidity
block, guys, is look how big it is. We
would have to enter here and our stop
loss would have to cover the whole low.
Now, we're on the hourly time frame.
Check this out. We have another
liquidity block, a refined area right
here.
Okay? And this is only using the 1 hour
time frame. Okay? But you can see how
price takes out this high, takes out
this low, leaving a liquidity block down
here. So, we can use that as a level to
put our stop loss. So, that shrinks our
SL quite a bit. Look at this. And this
is all doing this on the higher time
frames, by the way. Um, of course, your
RR can be much higher if you use the
lower time frames to refine after, but
that's not the purpose of this video. So
entry here. Same target back up to the
upside just like this. So let's see what
happens here. So remember we induce
buyers. We want to see price below the
below the low again.
And boom. We get tagged in and price
starts continuing to the upside. All
right. Rinse and repeat.
Okay. So now this entry moves up to the
upside. Remember we've taken out this
low inducing sellers. So any any
reactions at the highs deem them to be
false. Now I skipped a little bit far
ahead but maybe you guys can test on
your own here and see what I see. But
look
induce buyers. We trapped them. Look at
the engineered liquidity we have at the
highs. Okay, I hope you guys are
starting to see this on your own now.
And what do we have right below?
Go to the 15 minutes to kind of open
this up a little more for you guys.
We have another liquidity block right
here. Price takes out this high and then
price takes out this low. Boom. LB. So,
we can take our entry. As soon as price
stabs out this low, anywhere below this
black line I have marked on is a valid
buy. Why? LB'll be below. So, that
provides us a level to put our stop
loss. Just like this. So, let's clean up
a couple of these lines. Entry would be
like this. And as soon as price takes
out these highs, roll your stop loss.
Boom. Just like that. and targets.
Everything remains the same. Don't
forget about that higher time frame
narrative. Let's drag this target all
the way back up to the highs. Just like
this. Remember, every single bearish
reaction is only going to provide us
another opportunity to buy this asset
back up. Now, let's play this out a
little bit and see if we can find any
more entries. All right, so the market
actually ends up gapping and moving even
higher. Look at this so far. One entry
being here. And I hope you guys can see
the pattern as well. Look at this. every
single entry. Once liquidity is taken,
once liquidity is taken, once liquidity
is taken, it's the same thing over and
over and over. Now, we need to identify
another level of liquidity in order for
us to buy back up. Let's break down this
price action right here. Nothing really
to take yet. However, things to point
out for sure, we induce buyers. At the
least, you want to see price below this
low. Now, at the least, because since we
have induced buyers, people want to be
buying above this low. Therefore, we
want to see price below the low. and we
take the low out. Let's hop into the
15-minute time frame.
So, we take the low out. We're going to
hop into the hourly right now. And it
looks like since we have taken out highs
here, same thing occurs. We are inducing
buyers. We need to see price back down
at the lows. Remember, we're not going
to be buying once highs are taken out.
Okay? And price ends up selling off.
Now,
I almost want you guys to I almost want
to pause the video and show you guys um
well, actually hope you guys can
identify what has just happened. We have
induced buyers. I'm going to get my
paint tool out. Inducing them. And look
at this sell move back down to the
downside. We trapped this low, but not
only this low. Look to the left hand
side. This is where people make a lot of
mistakes. We have a
liquidity block left for us, which means
in any reaction in this area can provide
us a buy. Okay. And check this out. If I
use this blue box, drag it over. Look at
this. We have tapped into this liquidity
block perfectly. Remember the logic.
This is the accuracy. It's crazy.
Sometimes the precision on this, but the
logic of this is there's no liquidity
below this low. Therefore, why would we
run this low? So, we use that to your
advantage. We tap into these areas, take
entries off them. Boom. Entry would be
just like this. Stop loss would be below
the low.
You have intraday targets here, but
again, don't forget about that higher
time frame narrative. We are going to be
targeting the highs back up to the
upside just like this. So, you get
tagged in perfectly at that LB again.
Great intraday targets on the way back
up. Let's play this out and you get a
gorgeous reaction higher. Perfect stuff.
Let's hop back into the hourly and we
can make sense of what's going on. So,
price takes out these highs and now we
start getting a pullback. Remember the
first step we need to see a buildup of
liquidity. We need to see buyers
induced.
Okay. Now look to the left hand side.
The same thing over and over. High taken
out. Buyers are induced. Look how this
low respects this low. Building
liquidity here. All we got to do is plot
on a blue line. That is a form of
liquidity for us. Now here's the
buildup. Price approaches this level.
Okay, this whole we can mark it on as a
red box just to make it easy for you
guys.
So price approaches this whole level
here, taps into it once, twice, three
times. This is inducing buyers. Now
we're on the 1 hour time frame, guys. If
I drag this over, look, this is over 20
hours of price action. You can only
imagine how many people are entering
buys here. We understand that. So
therefore, we want to be buying below.
Okay, remember the market has literally
communicated to us that liquidity is
below this low. We are not guessing. We
are not predicting. We're waiting for
the market to tell us this. And if you
look to the left hand side, what do we
have? Another liquidity block here.
Remove this.
Drag it over. Another higher time frame
liquidity block here. How can we take
this entry?
Just like this. Stop loss below the low
to the left. Look at the same thing
across all entries, guys. When liquidity
is taken, stop covering liquidity block.
Liquidity taken, stop below liquidity
block all the way up into this last
entry here. And again, we are taking
that entry once the liquidity is taken
and we are targeting the highs up here.
Just like this. This is all done from
the higher time frames. Now, imagine
when the higher time frames intact, you
can actually find entries and hold them
for like 1 to 10, 1 to 15, 1 to 20. Does
this always happen? Of course not. But
when it does, you want to be able to
identify it and take advantage of it.
So, we've identified a form of
liquidity. Okay, we're going to be
taking an entry off of it. Look where
our stop loss is below the liquidity
block. We get tagged in.
Let's go back to the 4hour time frame
and we can get that higher time frame
perspective
and we move all the way back up to the
upside and fulfill that higher time
frame target. Check this out.
Boom. Just like that. Remember where we
were at the very beginning of this video
on the daily time frame all the way down
here. And we simply just use the higher
time frame to find entries on the way
back up. Remember, if you use all these
concepts in the higher time frame, it's
great because it provides you that
direction. Then when you go into the
lower time frames and apply refinements,
that's when the RRS can drastically
increase with literally just using the 1
hour and the 4 hour. Check this out. We
have a 1:6, we have a 1:7, a 1:19 here,
a 1:14, and a 1:3.6.
Okay, this is literally just using the 4
hour and 1 hour. And I think maybe we
had one refinement maybe on the
15-minute to find a smaller um LB. Other
than that, all higher time frame. Now,
imagine if you were able to refine those
entries into the lower, the RR
drastically goes up. All right, guys. If
you enjoyed today's video, please leave
a like and a comment down below. That
was a long one, but it was a good one,
okay? So, please rewatch it if you need
to. Let us know down in the comments
what other videos you guys want to see
from us. We'll talk soon.